American Association of Immunologists records
American Association of Immunologists records
- Series III. Committees, 1966-1992; .75 linear feet
  - Education/ High School Teacher Internships in Immunology 1990 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Education/ Summer Courses 1966 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Education/ Teacher Internship Program 1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Member List 1971 – 1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minority Affairs 1988 – 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Program 1988 – 198 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Program 1989 – 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Program/Annual Meeting 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Program/Meeting 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Program/Report 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Program/Report 1992 – 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Public Affairs 1989 – 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Public Affairs 1989 – 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Public Affairs/Correspondence 1989 – 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Publications/Correspondence 1989/11 – 1991/7 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Publications/Journal of Immunology 1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Publications/Meeting 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Selection (ad hoc)/Executive Director 1991 – 1992 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Veterinary Immunology 1989 – 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Veterinary Immunology 1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Series IV. Financial, 1921-1991; 1.25 linear feet
  There was a very limited amount of financial information in the collection. Membership dues ledgers and journals contained information regarding membership from 1946 – 1970.
  - Bank Deposit Records 1973 – 1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Certificates of Deposit 1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Investment Records 1991 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Journal 1946 – 1964 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Journal 1964 – 1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (A – C) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (D – G) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (H – L) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (M – R) (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (S – Z) (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Membership Dues Ledger (Resigned, Honorary, Deceased) 1921 – 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Statement 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Statement 1986, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Statement 1987, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Statement 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Statement and Budget 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Statement and Budget 1990 – 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series V. Historian, 1913-1988; 1.5 linear feet
  The series contains records compiled by Merrill Chase and Joe Saunders beginning in 1969. It has information files for most AAI Presidents as well as their photograph.
  - Subseries V.A. Historian Records, .5 linear feet
    The files contain correspondence, member lists, financial records, and other administrative records.
    - Constitution/Proposed Revision (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence 1969/2 – 1976/7 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Expenses 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Lists/ Honorary Members 1913 – 1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Lists/ Presidents 1913 – 1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Logo/AAI (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Notes 1969 – 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Subseries V.B. Personal Histories, 1946-1991; .5 linear feet
    The files contain information submitted to Merrill Chase during his project to document personal history files for all AAI Presidents. Dr. Joe Saunders acting as Executive Director and archivist expanded the histories. Files may contain correspondence, articles written or reports retained by the individual. The personal histories are listed in alpha order.
    - Avery, Dr. Oswald (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Boyne-Jones, Dr. Stanbope (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Benacerraf, Dr. Barry (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Berry, Dr. George (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Boyd, Dr. W.C. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Bronfenbrenner, Dr. Jakor (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Campbell, Dr. Dan (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Cannon, Dr. Paul (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Chase, Dr. Merrill (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Dingle, Dr. John (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Dixon, Dr. Frank (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Dochez, Dr. A.R (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Eagle, Dr. Harry (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Edsall, Dr. Goeffrey (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Felton, Dr. Lloyd (pneumonia vaccine) (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Fraser, Dr. Donald (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Fruend, Dr. Jules (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Gay, Dr. Frederick (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Good, Dr. Robert (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Heidelberger, Dr. Michael (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Hekteon, Dr. Ludwig (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Henle, Dr. Werner (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Hooker, Dr. Sanford (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Horsfall, Dr. Frank (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Jobling, Dr. James (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Kabat, Dr. Elvin (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Kolmer, Dr. John (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Kunkel, Dr. Henry George (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Lancefield, Dr. Rebecca (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Landsteiner, Dr. Karl (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Lennette, Dr. Edwin (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Longcope, Dr. Warfield (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Magill, Dr. Thomas (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Manwaring, Dr. Wilfred (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - McCoy, Dr. George (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Meyer, Dr. Karl (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Novy, Dr. Frederick (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Novy, Dr. Frederick/University of Michigan Department of Microbiology/Bacteriology (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Opie, Dr. Eugene (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Pappenheimer, Dr. A.M. (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Park, Dr. William (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Rivers, Dr. Thomas (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Ten Broeck, Dr. Carl (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Thorbecke, Dr. G. J. (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Wadsworth, Dr. Augustus (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Waksman, Dr. Byron (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Webb, Dr. Gerald (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Weil, Dr. Richard (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Wells, Dr. H. Gideon (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Zinser, Dr. Hans (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Subseries V.C. Photographs, 1913-1990; .5 linear feet
    Group photographs are filed first followed by individual photographs in alpha order.
    - Annual Meeting (no date) (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Annual Meeting 1988 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Annual Meeting 1990 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Notes and Expenses (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Presidents 1913 – 1948 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Presidents 1949 – 1987 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Amos, D. Bernard (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Austin, Frank (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Avery, Oswald (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Baltimore, David (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Boyne-Jones, Stanhope (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Behring – Heidelberger Lecturer 1990 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Benacerraf, Barey (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Berry, George (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Blake, Francis (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Bloom, Barry (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Boyd, William (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Brondz, Boris (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Bronfenbrenner, Jacques (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Campbell, Dan (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Cannon, Paul (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Capra, Don (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Coca, Arthur (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Chase, Merrill (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Cheever, Francis (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Cole, Rufus (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Coons, Albert (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Cooper, Max (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Dingle, John (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Dixon, Frank (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Dochez, Alphonse (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Eagle, Harry (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Eisen, Herman (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Enders, John (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Felton, Lloyd (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Fraser, Donald (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Francis, Jr., Thomas (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Fruend, Jules (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Gay, Frederick (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Good, Robert (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Habel, Karl (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Heidelberger, Michael (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Hektoen, Ludvig (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Henle, Werner (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Hitchens, A. Parker (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Hooker, Sanford (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Horsfall, Frank (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ishizaka, Kemishige (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Jobling, James (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Kabat, Elvin (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Kolmer, John (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Kashland, Marion (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Kunkel, Henry (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Lancefield, Rebecca (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Landsteiner, Karl (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Lennette, Elwin (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Lepow, Irwin (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Longcope, Norfield (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - MacCleod, Colin (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Magill, Thomas (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Manwaring, Wilfred (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Mayer, M.M. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - McCoy, George (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - McDevitt, Hugh (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Metzger, Henry (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Meyer, Karl (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Miller, Jacques (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Nisonoff, A. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Novy, Frederick (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Opie, Eugene (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Pappenheim, A. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Park, William (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Paul, William (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Pierce, Carl (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Rivers, Thomas (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Schulz, G. & McDevitt, H. (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Schwick, G (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Shevach, Ethan (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Shreffler, Donald (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Smadel, Joseph (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Synnott, Martin (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Talmage, David (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Ten Broeck, Carl (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Thorbecke, Jeanette (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Uhr, Jonathan (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Vaughn, Victor (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Wadsworth, Augustus (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Waksman, Byron (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Webb, Gerald (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Webb, Gerald with Patch, Pottenger, Brown,O.H., Wright, A., May, A. (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Weil, Richard (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Wells, H. Gideon (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Wright, Almroth Edward (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Zinsser, Hans (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Series VI. Publications, 1933-1995; 2.5 linear feet
  This series contains a mix of publications from AAI, FASEB, and other scientific organizations as well as individual authors. Included are journals, newsletters, meeting programs, articles and full length books. There are two folders of correspondence regarding AAI publications. They are listed in alpha order.
  - American Academy Allergy and Immunology Meeting Program 1992 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - AAI Annual Meeting Program 1978 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - AAI Annual Meeting Program 1984 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - AAI Newsletters 1971 – 1972 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - AAI Newsletters 1973 – 1975 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - AAI Newsletters 1976 – 1978 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - AAI Newsletters 1979 – 1981 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - AAI Newsletters 1982 – 1984 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - AAI Newsletters 1985 – 1986 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - AAI Newsletters 1987 – 1988 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - AAI Newsletters 1989 – 1991 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - AAI Program Book 1960 – 1987 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - AAI’s Role – 1913 to 1988 – in the First Century of Immunology (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Articles (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Brochures (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Brucelosis (M. Ruiz Castaneda) 1986 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - The Bulletin (Howard Hughes Medical Institute) 1990/9, 1991/1 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Cancer Center Report Spring 1990 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - China Exchange News 1989/9 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence/Joe Saunders 1998 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Distinguished Woman Physician/Scientist 1988, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Forecast Fall 1985 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Growing Up with Virology (Gertrude Henle, M.D.) (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Henry Sewell Physiologist and Physician (Webb&Powell) 1946 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - History of Immunology (Arthur Silverstein) 1983 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - History of American Society for Experimental Pathology (Esmond Long) 1972 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Immunological Concepts (David Talmadge) 1986 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Immunology Meetings and News 1967/2 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - The Immunologist 1994, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Immuno News (Thorbecke) 1990/6 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - International Congress of Immunology Abstracts 1995/7 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - International Congress of Immunology Program 1995/7 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Journal of Immunology 1988/12 – 1989/2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Journal of Immunology 1988/10 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Journal of Immunology/M. Heidelberger 1988/5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Immunology/Presidential Addresses (Bloom, Nisonoff, Thorbecke) 1986, 1990, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Journal of the American Medical Association 1982/11 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory Science Writing Fellowship Programs 1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Maximilliano Ruiz-Casteneda 1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - National Coalition on Immune System Disorders/Program 1987/1 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases 1991/1 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Nutrition Notes (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - The Prescription of Literature (Webb) 1933 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Regulatory Elements of the Immune System 1992 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - R.J.R. Nabisco Research Scholars Award 1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Sandoz Focus on Immunology 1990/6 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Veterinary Immunology Newsletter 1986/6 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Warlord’s Revenge – Can You Dig It? 1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - World Health 1988/1 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Series VII. Affiliated Societies, 1967-1991; 1.5 linear feet
  This series consists mostly of materials from the umbrella organization Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (FASEB) which AAI was a member. It is arranged in alpha order followed by date order. Most materials are from the 1980s.
  - FASEB/Annual Meeting Program 1988 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - FASEB/Annual Meeting Reports 1987, 1988, 1 1990, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - FASEB/Biomedical Research Funding Form 1991 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - FASEB/Committee Reports (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - FASEB/Concensus Conference 1991 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - FASEB/Constitution (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - FASEB/Correspondence 1990/4 – 10 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - FASEB/Correspondence (Federation Board) 1961/6 – 1967/12 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - FASEB/Correspondence (Federation Board) 1989 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - FASEB/Meeting 1989 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - FASEB/Meeting 1990 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - FASEB/Program Committee 1987 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1965 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1966 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1967 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1968 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1969 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1970 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1971 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1972 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1973 - 1974 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1974 – 1975 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1975 - 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1977 - 1977 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1977 – 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - FASEB/Publications/Directory of Membership 1978 –1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - FASEB/Publications/Journal 1989/8 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - FASEB/Publications/Meeting Program 1979, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - FASEB/Publications/Meeting Program 1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - FASEB/Publications/Meeting Program 1983, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - FASEB/Publications/Meeting Program 1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - FASEB/Publications/Meeting Program 1986, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - FASEB/Publications/Newsletters 1987/2, 1988/2, 1988/6, 1989/3, 1990/2, 1990/5 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - FASEB/Public Affairs Committee 1977 – 1978 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - International Congress of Immunology/Meeting (First) 1971 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - International Congress of Immunology/Meeting 1989, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - International Congress of Immunology/Meeting 1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - International Union of Immunological Societies/Correspondence and Reports 1971 – 1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - International Union of Immunological Societies/Correspondence and Reports 1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - New York Academy of Science Conference/Abstract Control 1989 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Series VIII. Video and Audio Tapes, 1970-1991; .4 linear feet
  The series consists mostly of audio cassette tapes of annual and council meetings from 1986 – 1991.
  - Audio Tapes/Annual Meetings 1986, 1987, 1988, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Audio Tapes/Council Meetings 1986 – 1991 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Audio Tapes/Teleconference 1987/8 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Video Tapes/ Cohen, Sheldon (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Video Tapes/ 1975/5 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Video Tapes/ Heidelberger Lecture 1970/9 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Video Tapes/Talmadge, David/Interview, The First Century of Immunology, Mechanisms of Graft Rejections (Box 12, Folder 7)